<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pci on KenCochrane.net</title>
    <link>http://www.kencochrane.net/tags/pci/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pci on KenCochrane.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.kencochrane.net/tags/pci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Developers Guide to PCI Compliant Web applications</title>
      <link>http://www.kencochrane.net/blog/2012/01/developers-guide-to-pci-compliant-web-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kencochrane.net/blog/2012/01/developers-guide-to-pci-compliant-web-applications/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;last updated: 12-07-2012 by Ken Cochrane&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: 12-07-2012&lt;/strong&gt; I have added the youtube video and slides from a
recent talk I did on Building PCI Complaint Django Applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: 04-05-2012&lt;/strong&gt; This article has been &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ituring.com.cn/article/1372&#34;&gt;translated into
chinese&lt;/a&gt; , by Wujun Shen
(吴峻申)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started working at &lt;a href=&#34;http://CashStar.com&#34;&gt;CashStar.com&lt;/a&gt;
three and a half years ago, I had heard about PCI before, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t
really know what that meant. Since we were building an ecommerce
platform that was going to be accepting credit cards over the internet,
I knew we needed to make sure we were fully PCI compliant. We were a
startup, we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much money, and any mistake could kill the
company. Since I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be the one to make the mistake, I spent
a lot of time doing research on PCI, and what it took to make sure your
web application was secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I did was a simple web search, and I was surprised
to find out that there really wasn&amp;rsquo;t much information available. Most of
the information that was available, wasn&amp;rsquo;t easily understandable, and
was a little vague. There were companies that you could hire, that would
guide you through the process, but since we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much money, they
weren&amp;rsquo;t an option for us. So I did what any geek in my situation would
do, I spent a bunch of my time reading and researching as much as I
could on PCI, and figured my way through the PCI hell, until we were
fully PCI compliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal with this blog post is write all of my information down, so that
I can hopefully help others through the process, and also to serve as a
reminder to me, so that when I need to do this again in the future, I
will remember every last detail. I hoping to keep this as a sort of live
document, and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep it up to date as time goes forward and
things change. If you notice something is incorrect or I&amp;rsquo;m missing
something, please leave a comment and I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to update the post
as soon as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-pci:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;What is PCI?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing most people ask is &amp;ldquo;What is PCI?&amp;rdquo;. PCI is short for the
Payment Card Industry Security Standards Council. PCI consists of
American Express, Discover Financial Services, JCB, MasterCard, and
Visa, and was formed on Sept 7th, 2006.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of creating the PCI SSC, was to come up with a common
set of security standards that merchants could use to better protect
themselves against hackers. The PCI SSC came up with the Payment Card
Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS), which consists of 12
requirements, and many sub-requirements that merchants would need to
follow in order to accept debit, credit, prepaid, ATM or POS cards from
the PCI SSC members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-was-pci-created:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Why was PCI created?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was created in response to a spike in data security breaches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives merchants a guide to help them make sure they are following
best security practices when it comes to card holder data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;does-pci-affect-me:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Does PCI affect me?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you accept payment online or over the phone with credit/debit
cards?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the credit card information posted to YOUR server?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you store credit card information, encrypted or not?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you said yes to any of those, then PCI affects you in one way or
another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pci-dss-requirements:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;PCI DSS Requirements&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the list of 12 requirements. As you look them over, you will
notice that most of them aren&amp;rsquo;t that complicated, and you might already
be doing thing already. Most of them are just common sense, but it is
amazing how many people still don&amp;rsquo;t do things, even if it is common
sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install and maintain a firewall configuration to protect cardholder
data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not use vendor-supplied defaults for system passwords and other
security parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protect stored cardholder data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encrypt transmission of cardholder data across open, public networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use and regularly update anti-virus software on all systems commonly
affected by malware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop and maintain secure systems and applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restrict access to cardholder data by business need-to-know&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign a unique ID to each person with computer access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restrict physical access to cardholder data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Track and monitor all access to network resources and cardholder
data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regularly test security systems and processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain a policy that addresses information security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pci-in-layman-s-terms:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;PCI in Layman&amp;rsquo;s Terms&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Merchants, regardless if credit card data is stored, must
achieve and maintain compliance at all times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merchants cannot store certain credit card information including
CVV, track data, magnetic strip or PIN data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you store permitted credit card data, you need to store it in a
secure way following the PCI security standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-does-pci-certification-work:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;How does PCI Certification work?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PCI Certification works like this. If you want to accept credit or debit
cards you need to agree that you will maintain PCI certification at all
times. There are a couple of ways to confirm that you are certified. You
need to either fill out a Self-Assessment Questionnaire (SAQ) or a
Report on Compliance (RoC). I&amp;rsquo;ll go over the difference in a little bit,
but the important part to remember is that you need to fill out some
paper work, and then usually submit that paperwork to whomever requests
it, usually the company that processes your credit cards and handles
your merchant account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill out a Self-Assessment Questionnaire (SAQ) and Find out what
level you are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you follow all recommendations for that level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix any issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attestation of Compliance (if self assessing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External Auditor (if needed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-get-started:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;How to get started?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the individuals that will be responsible for PCI
compliance in your organization and assemble a team that includes
members from each area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine your merchant level (1-4).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine which SAQ your organization will need to complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate whether your organization will try to achieve compliance
internally or engage with aQualified Security Assessor (QSA).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage with an Approved Scanning Vendor (ASV) to start the
required external IP vulnerability scans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure that your organization has an Information Security
Policy and that it is being enforced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immediately address any significant deficiencies discovered during
the assessment or scan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retain record of self-assessments, scans, and
follow-up activities. Be prepared to provide these documents
upon request.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-pci-level-am-i:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;What PCI Level am I?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 4 PCI compliance level&amp;rsquo;s, and how many transactions you
process a year will determine which level you are in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;merchant-level:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Merchant Level&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 1&lt;/strong&gt; : Merchants processing over 6 million Visa transactions
annually (all channels) or Global merchants identified as Level 1 by any
Visa region&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 2&lt;/strong&gt; : Merchants processing 1 million to 6 million Visa
transactions annually (all channels)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 3&lt;/strong&gt; : Merchants processing 20,000 to 1 million Visa e-commerce
transactions annually&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 4&lt;/strong&gt; : Merchants processing less than 20,000 Visa e-commerce
transactions annually and all other merchants processing up to 1 million
Visa transactions annually&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 1&lt;/strong&gt; : Onsite Security Assessment Required Annually, Network
Vulnerability Scan required Quarterly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 2&lt;/strong&gt; : Onsite Security Assessment at Merchants Discretion,
Self-Assessment Questionnaire Required Annually, Network Vulnerability
Scan Required Quarterly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 3&lt;/strong&gt; : Self-Assessment Questionnaire Required Annually, Network
Vulnerability Scan Required Quarterly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level 4&lt;/strong&gt; : Self-Assessment Questionnaire Required Annually, Network
Vulnerability Scan Required Quarterly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;roc-or-saq:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;RoC or SAQ?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a Level 1 then you need to fill out a RoC, if you are level
2, 3 or 4, then you can fill out an SAQ. There are some exceptions to
these rules, for example, if you have had a security breach in the past,
the credit card companies might require that you complete a RoC even if
you aren&amp;rsquo;t a level 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;report-on-compliance-roc:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Report on Compliance (RoC)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you process more than six million credit cards per year (Level 1),
you are required to have an on-site PCI assessment and Report on
Compliance (RoC) issued by a Qualified Security Assessor (QSA). Other
Level 2 organizations may also be required to submit a RoC or choose to
do so in anticipation of becoming a Level 1 merchant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QSA’s can be engaged to provide this annual review. It includes a review
of established processes and procedures for networks, servers and
databases in scope for PCI compliance. The engagement involves
interviews with stakeholders in your organization, a review of
supporting documentation, validation of compliance initiatives and
completion of the report itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QSA’s usually encourage their PCI Customers to use a PCI compliance
management solution throughout the year. This will assist them with
maintaining compliance and should make the on-site engagement and the
completion of the RoC faster and smoother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;self-assement-questionnaire:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Self-Assement Questionnaire&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 5 SAQ categories, depending on which category that you fall
into, the paper work might be real easy, it might take a lot longer.
Here are the 5 categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAQ-A&lt;/strong&gt; : Card-not-present (e-commerce or mail/telephone-order)
merchants, all cardholder data functions outsourced. This would never
apply to face-to-face merchants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAQ-B&lt;/strong&gt; : Imprint-only merchants with no electronic cardholder data
storage, or standalone, dial- out terminal merchants with no electronic
cardholder data storage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAQ-C-VT&lt;/strong&gt; : Merchants using only web-based virtual terminals, no
electronic cardholder data storage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAQ-C&lt;/strong&gt; : Merchants with payment application systems connected to the
Internet, no electronic cardholder data storage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAQ-D&lt;/strong&gt; : All other merchants not included in descriptions for SAQ
types A through C above, and all service providers defined by a payment
brand as eligible to complete an SAQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we are only talking about web applications here, you will most
likely only fall into either A, C, or D. Once you know your level you
will need to fill out the SAQ for that category. Once you are done you
need an Attestation of compliance as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a helpful guide to help you figure out what category you a fall
into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;saq-a:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;SAQ-A&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of different parts to A, but the big one, is that the
credit card data never touches your servers. The easiest way to do this
is to redirect people to someone else&amp;rsquo;s servers when you want them to
enter credit card data. This is common with Paypal, google checkout and
Amazon payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way around this is to have your payment page hosted by your
credit card gateway. An example of this is authorize.net&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.authorize.net/solutions/merchantsolutions/merchantservices/simplecheckout/&#34;&gt;Simple
Checkout&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A third way of doing this is what is called &amp;ldquo;transparent redirect&amp;rdquo; or
&amp;ldquo;Direct Post&amp;rdquo;,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.braintreepayments.com/services/pci-compliance&#34;&gt;BrainTreePayments&lt;/a&gt;
was the first to make this popular, but since then
&lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.authorize.net/api/dpm&#34;&gt;Authorize.net&lt;/a&gt; has also added
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally the last way, is basically similar to the third way, but it
uses javascript to encrypt the credit card data, send it to the credit
card processor, and then populate the form with unique tokens, which
will be used later on. This approach is used by
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stripe.com&#34;&gt;stripe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BrainTree + livingsocial talk about this new approach of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.braintreepayments.com/devblog/end-to-end-encryption&#34;&gt;end to end
encryption of credit card
data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;saq-c:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;SAQ-C&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are hosting the payment form on your own server, and when you hit
submit on that form it goes to your server, where you parse the form,
get the credit card details out of the fields, build up your request and
then send it to the credit card processor yourself. Then you are at
least a C. Even if you aren&amp;rsquo;t storing the data, because it is available
in your computer memory, and you are touching it with your code, there
is risk that something could happen and you would be able to get access
to the credit card data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;saq-d:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;SAQ-D&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t fall into the other categories then you are a D. SAQ D is
sometimes referred to as ROC light, because any organization that has to
fill out SAQ D is essentially going through all 12 PCI DSS requirements,
albeit on a reduced scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-much-does-pci-cost:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;How much does PCI Cost?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is really hard to get an accurate value for this because it will be
different for everyone, but according to BrainTree here is a chart on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.braintreepayments.com/blog/what-does-it-cost-to-become-pci-compliant&#34;&gt;how much it costs to become PCI
Compliant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Level   # of Trans   Scope    Compliance   Audit type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1       6M+           \$125K   \$586K       onsite
  2       1M-6M         \$105K   \$267K       SAQ
  3       20K-1M        \$44K    \$81K        SAQ
  4       &amp;lt; 20K      ?        ?            SAQ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;external-audits:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;External Audits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Level     Cost Per Year&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low End   \$20K-\$30K
  Average   \$225K
  Top 10%   \$500K+&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are big enough or unlucky enough to require an external audit, it
isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be cheap. Audits last a few weeks or more onsite, and
cost anywhere from \$20K-\$30K on the low end. They average around
\$225K a year, and about 10% of the audits cost over \$500K. As you can
see this is a really expensive annual cost, and should be avoided if
possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also important to point out that this is just the cost of the
audit itself, if they find anything wrong in the audit, you will need to
pay to fix any of the issues before they will certify you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Here are some links where I got my data.&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.networkworld.com/news/2010/030110-pci-compliance-audit-cost.html&#34;&gt;http://www.networkworld.com/news/2010/030110-pci-compliance-audit-cost.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.elementps.com/element_payment_solutions/2009/02/pci-compliance-costs.html&#34;&gt;http://blog.elementps.com/element_payment_solutions/2009/02/pci-compliance-costs.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infosecisland.com/blogview/12356-Five-Questions-to-Ask-Your-PCI-Auditor-Before-You-Hire-Them.html&#34;&gt;https://www.infosecisland.com/blogview/12356-Five-Questions-to-Ask-Your-PCI-Auditor-Before-You-Hire-Them.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pci-2-0:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;PCI 2.0&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On October 26th 2010, PCI DSS version 2.0 was released. Here are some of
the highlights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;132 changes, 2 new ones, the rest are clarifications or additional
guidelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added more guidelines around virtualization, and how it affects PCI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon web services (AWS) is now a Level 1 PCI compliant
data center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;nitty-gritty:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Nitty Gritty&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know what PCI is all about, lets get down to the nitty
gritty. The most common questions I&amp;rsquo;m asked is what is the easiest way
to become PCI certified. Here is what I tell people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, avoid handling credit card data if you can help it. It has
become a lot easier lately with Braintree and stripe. Years ago before
these solutions were available, the only way to do it was to use an ugly
hosted payment page on your credit card gateway, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very
good, and hard to integrate, so most people didn&amp;rsquo;t use those solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have no excuse, let the credit card processor handle all of the
credit card data, and it will make your life easier. If you want to see
how much easier, go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org&#34;&gt;PCI security
standards&lt;/a&gt; website and download
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/documents/pci_saq_a_v2.doc&#34;&gt;SAQ
A&lt;/a&gt; and
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/documents/pci_saq_c_v2.doc&#34;&gt;SAQ
C&lt;/a&gt;
docs. You will notice that the SAQ A is much easier, and a lot less of a
hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As great as the Briantree and stripe solutions are they can&amp;rsquo;t solve all
problems. One common problem is accepting credit card data over an API,
more and more common these days with mobile applications. If you can&amp;rsquo;t
use one of the other solutions for one reason or another, you can check
out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.akamai.com/html/solutions/security/edge_tokenization.html&#34;&gt;Edge
Tokenization&lt;/a&gt;
from Akamai, it will work for both API and web based payment forms. It
is pretty expensive, but if you are already using some of akamai&amp;rsquo;s other
solutions then this might not be as big of an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you still need/want to accept credit card data on your own server
after everything that I said above, then you are going to need to know
about some other things. For example, here are a list of common mistakes
that most people make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;common-pci-mistakes:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Common PCI Mistakes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of common mistakes most people make. I&amp;rsquo;m listing them
here so that you can catch these mistakes before it is too late. If I
missed any, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;storing-credit-card-information-in-plain-text:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Storing credit card information in plain text&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, you should never store credit card information, but if you have
to, you should always encrypt the data, so that if someone gets ahold of
your data, they won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see it unless they put in a lot of
effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;default-passwords-not-changed:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Default passwords not changed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m always surprised to here how weak peoples passwords are, and how
most of the time they are still using the first one that was given to
them when they started. That is why if you are the one generating a
password, make it a secure one, so that if the people don&amp;rsquo;t change the
password like you told them too, it will at least be a secure one to
begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are really good password management tools on the market today, I
recommend using one of them. One of my favorites is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://agilebits.com/onepassword&#34;&gt;1password&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;remove-all-programs-not-needed-from-your-servers:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Remove all programs not needed from your servers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple reasons why you would want to remove any
programs/software from your computer if you are not using it. The first
one, it will take up less space, and if it isn&amp;rsquo;t running it will free up
processor and RAM, a faster system is always good. The second reason is
so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to maintain the security patches for something
you aren&amp;rsquo;t using. So, the first step you should do when you bring a new
server online is to remove all of the stuff you aren&amp;rsquo;t using. You can
always add it back later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-a-firewall:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Use a Firewall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should always use a firewall, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if it is a hardware
firewall or a software firewall, use it, and never turn it off. In some
of my production systems I run both a hardware firewall coming into my
private network and then a software firewall on each system. Some people
think this is overkill, but I would rather be safer then sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just running the firewall is only part of it, you need to know how the
firewall is setup, and why. You should always have a document around
with a list of which ports are open and why. This will be very helpful
later on, when you get audited and they want to know what ports are
open, and the reasons for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should do a quarterly review of your firewalls to make sure they
match your documentation, and to see if any of the ports that were
previously open still need to be open. Systems change over time, and
sometimes you will remove a service that isn&amp;rsquo;t needed anymore, and when
that happens you should also block the port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also use a service like &lt;a href=&#34;http://cloudflare.com&#34;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt;
that protect your website from a range of online threats from spammers
to SQL injection to DDOS. It is easy to setup, and your code changes
should be minimal at most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;poorly-coded-websites:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Poorly coded websites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the programmers who are writing your web application aren&amp;rsquo;t careful,
and don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are doing, they could write bad code which
could result in SQL injection and other vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cross Site Scripting (XSS) is becoming a more and more common way of
attacking websites these days, so make sure you are careful of that as
well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you always conduct code reviews, and use application
penetration testing before you put your code into production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lack-of-monitoring-and-logging:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Lack of monitoring and logging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is amazing how many companies have no system or application
monitoring, it is like they are running blind, they have no idea when
something is going wrong until their customers tell them. You should
have as much monitoring and logging as possible, so that you know what
is happening with your system at all times. If you don&amp;rsquo;t log when things
are going well, then when stuff starts going bad you will have no idea
what things are suppose to look like when things are good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of tools that will help you with your logging and
monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pingdom.com&#34;&gt;Pingdom&lt;/a&gt; Is a website monitoring tool, they
will tell you when your site is down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nagios.org/&#34;&gt;Nagios&lt;/a&gt; offers complete monitoring and
alerting for servers, switches, applications, and services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cacti.net/&#34;&gt;Cacti&lt;/a&gt; is a complete network graphing
solution designed to harness the power of RRDTool&amp;rsquo;s data storage and
graphing functionality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dcramer/sentry&#34;&gt;Sentry&lt;/a&gt; Open Source realtime
event logging and aggregation platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://loggly.com/&#34;&gt;Loggly&lt;/a&gt; Log management cloud service for
centralized log search and analysis, time series data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://graphite.wikidot.com/&#34;&gt;graphite&lt;/a&gt; Scalable Realtime Graphing
server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://collectd.org/&#34;&gt;collectd&lt;/a&gt; is a daemon which collects system
performance statistics periodically and provides mechanisms to store
the values in a variety of ways, for example in RRD files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mmonit.com/&#34;&gt;monit&lt;/a&gt; Easy, proactive monitoring of Linux/Unix
systems, network and cloud services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://munin-monitoring.org/&#34;&gt;munin&lt;/a&gt; Munin is a networked resource
monitoring tool that can help analyze resource trends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://NewRelic.com&#34;&gt;New Relic&lt;/a&gt; is the only tool you need to
pinpoint and solve performance issues in your Ruby, Java, .NET, PHP
and Python apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://PagerDuty.com&#34;&gt;Pager Duty&lt;/a&gt; Phone &amp;amp; SMS alerting and on-call
scheduling for Nagios, Zenoss, Munin, Monit, and most other IT
monitoring tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;missing-security-patches:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Missing security patches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important that you regularly schedule applying all security
patches on all of your systems. This is a no brainer but it is amazing
how much this doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also subscribe to all of the security alert email lists for
any of the products that you are using, as well as paying attention the
following list of websites below. The sooner you get notified of a
potential problem the sooner you can fix it before it effects you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.us-cert.gov/cas/&#34;&gt;http://www.us-cert.gov/cas/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://seclists.org/&#34;&gt;http://seclists.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sans.org/newsletters/&#34;&gt;http://www.sans.org/newsletters/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-using-ssl-for-payment-page:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Not using SSL for payment page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another no brainer, but sometimes it happens. You should add code to
your web applications that check to make sure that the payment pages are
served over SSL, if not, do a redirect to the SSL version of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An easy way to do this is to serve the whole site over SSL all of the
time, and then do a simple redirect with your web server from port 80
(http) over to port 443(https). This will guarantee that all traffic is
served over SSL all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;logging-payment-information:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Logging payment information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most common mistakes that I see is when someone has their
logging setup to print out data from the payment form to the logs. This
is great for debugging purposes but bad for PCI. You should always strip
out the important information out of the request before logging it. You
can replace the credit card number with **last4 and get the same
result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common mistake that is similar is dumping all of the data when
there is an error and emailing it to the developers. If you do this as
well, make sure you strip out the credit card info first or else that
person&amp;rsquo;s credit card information is now emailed all over the place,
which isn&amp;rsquo;t good at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credit-card-data-that-can-be-stored:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Credit card data that can be stored&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important that you NEVER EVER store credit card information in the
database, even if it is encrypted. It isn&amp;rsquo;t worth the hassle, risk and
the cost of handling an external audit. But if you absolutely insist,
here is something you need to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If for some reason you ignore my advice and decide to store credit card
data anyway, here is a little chart that will show you which data is
allowed to be stored, and If it needs to be encrypted or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to 3.3 Mask PAN when displayed (the first six and last
four digits are the maximum number of digits to be displayed). That
means, you need to do something like this *****1234 Visa instead
of the actual credit card number. This is pretty common these days.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to 3.4 : Render PAN unreadable anywhere it is stored
(including on portable digital media, backup media, and in logs) by
using any of the following approaches:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One-way hashes based on strong cryptography (hash must be of
the entire PAN) [ One-way hash functions such as the Secure
Hash Algorithm (SHA) based on strong cryptography can be used
to render cardholder data unreadable. Hash functions are
appropriate when there is no need to retrieve the original
number (one-way hashes are irreversible) To complicate the
creation of rainbow tables it is recommended, but not a
requirement, that a salt value be input to the hash function
in addition to the PAN.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Truncation (hashing cannot be used to replace the truncated
segment of PAN)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Index tokens and pads (pads must be securely stored)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong cryptography with associated key-management processes
and procedures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+
|                     | Storage Permitted    | Protection Required      |
+=====================+======================+==========================+
|                     | &lt;strong&gt;Cardholder Data&lt;/strong&gt;  |                          |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+
| Account Number      | &amp;gt; Y                  | &amp;gt; Y                      |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+
| Cardholder data     | &amp;gt; Y                  | &amp;gt; N                      |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+
| Expiration Date     | &amp;gt; Y                  | &amp;gt; N                      |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+
| Service Code        | &amp;gt; Y                  | &amp;gt; N                      |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+
|                     | **Authentication   | ta**                   |
|                     | Da                   |                          |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+
| Magnetic Strip      | &amp;gt; N                  | &amp;gt; n/a                    |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+
| CVV                 | &amp;gt; N                  | &amp;gt; n/a                    |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+
| Pin Data            | &amp;gt; N                  | &amp;gt; n/a                    |
+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-+&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;+&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tokenization:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Tokenization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to store credit card information, it is best to use a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tokenization_(data_security&#34;&gt;tokenization&lt;/a&gt;)
service instead of storing it yourself. You store the credit card
information in their system. They give you a unique token that you use
for all future transactions against that credit card. These types of
service are pretty common these days, just ask your credit card
processor if they have such a service. Here are a couple of credit card
processors that provide this sort of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.authorize.net/solutions/merchantsolutions/merchantservices/cim/&#34;&gt;Authorize.net
CIM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.braintreepayments.com/services/payment-gateway&#34;&gt;BrainTree
Vault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stripe.com/docs/stripe.js&#34;&gt;Stripe.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://recurly.com&#34;&gt;Recurly.com subscription based billing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;data-centers:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Data Centers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are dealing with PCI compliance you need to worry about the
full stack, not just your application, but also the server the
application lives on, the network your server is connected to, and the
data center your server lives in. The first thing you will want to do is
contact your your hosting provider to see if they are PCI compliant, and
if so, you might want to request a copy of their PCI documents for your
records (you might need them later). Usually hosting providers that are
PCI compliant brag about it on their web pages, so that is usually a
good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smaller the hosting company that you deal with the smaller the
chance you will be PCI compliant. If you are just using a shared hosting
plan, and paying \$20/month, most likely you are not compliant. You
might get lucky, but I doubt it. If you are using a PAAS or a cloud
provider, you will also most likely be out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hosting-in-the-cloud:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Hosting in the Cloud&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com&#34;&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/a&gt; (AWS) has recently had
their data centers meet PCI compliance, but what is important to note is
that just because the data center in compliant, doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that your
application is going to be. If you put your application on EC2, and you
accept credit card data that is getting processed on those EC2
instances, you will need to make sure that you also have an Intrusion
Detection System (IDS) amongst other things in place or else you aren&amp;rsquo;t
PCI compliant. All of the good IDS&amp;rsquo;s are hardware based, and have
someone monitoring the traffic at all times. You can&amp;rsquo;t install those
systems in AWS, so you will need to rely on a software based solution,
which isn&amp;rsquo;t as good, and adds another layer of complexity to your
network stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://Rackspace.com&#34;&gt;RackSpace&lt;/a&gt; offers a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rackspace.com/hosting_solutions/hybrid_hosting/&#34;&gt;hybrid cloud
hosting&lt;/a&gt;
setup, which allows you to have hardware firewall, IDS, Load balancers,
cloud web servers and hardware database servers. But even in this setup,
it isn&amp;rsquo;t PCI compliant, at least I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to get RackSpace to
tell me it is yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other cloud providers that might be able to offer you a
complete PCI compliant solution, but I&amp;rsquo;m guessing they are going to cost
more money. If you know of one, please let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll update this.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.terremark.com/services/security-services/governance-risk-compliance-management/pci-compliance.aspx&#34;&gt;Terremark&lt;/a&gt;
might have something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;security-scanners:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Security Scanners&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key part of the PCI certification is the 3rd party security scanning
requirement. Basically you have to pay one of the certified and approved
security scanning companies to scan you network, server, application
every so often, and if it finds any issues, you will need to fix those,
and scan again until you pass their tests. Once you pass the scans they
will give you a certificate that you can attach to the rest of your PCI
documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have used a company called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.controlscan.com&#34;&gt;ControlScan&lt;/a&gt;
in the past, and I have also used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qualys.com&#34;&gt;Qualys&lt;/a&gt;, but
I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are a ton of others out there. Pick the one that looks
the best for you. Here is a link to a list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/approved_companies_providers/approved_scanning_vendors.php&#34;&gt;PCI approved scanning
vendors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;intrusion-detection-systems:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Intrusion Detection Systems&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS) basically sit in front of your network
and watch all of the network traffic coming into your network. It looks
to see if it notices anything out of the ordinary, of if people are
trying to use known attacks, and if it finds something it will let you
know. They have hard ware and software based solutions. They range in
price from free to thousands of dollars a month. They all have different
features and abilities, it is best to pick one that has what you need,
that you are comfortable maintaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alertlogic.com&#34;&gt;AlertLogic&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; hardware based
IDS, and it works well. They have a pool of on call people who monitor
the devices and if something gets triggered they look it over, and act
accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hashing-credit-card-numbers:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Hashing credit card numbers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a great example on why hashing credit card numbers isn&amp;rsquo;t a good
idea. I&amp;rsquo;m borrowing some of this from these two links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.oreilly.com/rails2011/public/schedule/detail/19466&#34;&gt;http://en.oreilly.com/rails2011/public/schedule/detail/19466&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.integrigy.com/security-resources/whitepapers/Integrigy_Hashing_Credit_Card_Numbers_Unsafe_Practices.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.integrigy.com/security-resources/whitepapers/Integrigy_Hashing_Credit_Card_Numbers_Unsafe_Practices.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because you are following PCI rules doesn’t mean you are
invincible, you still have to use your common sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PCI DSS section 3.4
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pcisecuritystandards.org/pdfs/pci_audit_procedures_v1-1.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt;:
Render PAN, at minimum, unreadable anywhere it is stored .. by using
any of the following approaches: Strong one-way hash functions (hashed
indexes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verify that data is rendered unreadable using one of the following
methods: one-way hashes (hashed indexes) such as SHA-1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically what this is saying is that you are allowed to store the
first 6 digits of a credit card (BIN) as well as the last 4 digits of
the credit card. Credit cards are between 13-16 digits in length and
the last digit is the check digit (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luhn_algorithm&#34;&gt;Luhn
algorithm&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see how hard it would be to figure out this credit card number.
4012888888881881&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we start with a full 16 digits that means that we have ￼10\^16 or
10,000,000,000,000,000 (10 Quadrillion) Possible Card Numbers, if we
didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about the card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we are storing the credit card type, we know this is a visa, visa
credit cards all start with a 4 so that means that is could be
4XXXXXXXXXXXXXXX or ￼4,000,000,000,000,000 (4 Quadrillion) Possible Card
Numbers, we just cut the number of possible cards in more then half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we also store the bin (first 6 digits) and the last 4 digits, then it
would look like this. 401288*&lt;em&gt;*&lt;/em&gt;**1881 or 1,000,000 (1 million)
possible card numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with that lets try to write a simple cracker (Ruby)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode ruby&#34;&gt;hashed_card_number = &#39;62163a017b168ad4a229c64ae1bed6ffd5e8fb2d&#39;
masked_card_number = &#39;401288******1881&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode ruby&#34;&gt;require &#39;digest/sha1&#39;

def reverse_hashed_card_number( hashed_card_number, first_six, last_four)
    0.upto(999_999) do |i|
        card_number_to_test = &amp;quot;#{first_six}%06d#{last_four}&amp;quot; % i
        hashed_to_test = Digest::SHA1.hexdigest(card_number_to_test)
        if hashed_card_number == hashed_card_number_to_test
          return card_number_to_test
        end
    end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s run it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode ruby&#34;&gt;Benchmark.measure do
  puts reverse_hashed_card_number(
    &#39;62163a017b168ad4a229c64ae1bed6ffd5e8fb2d&#39;,
    &#39;401288&#39;,
    &#39;1881&#39;
) end.real
4012888888881881
=&amp;gt; 5.33522081375122
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 5.3 seconds it was able to crack the hash, if you use only a SHA-1
hash. We could possibly make it even faster if we did a luhn check on
the number before we ran the hash, and if the luhn check fails then we
know the number isn&amp;rsquo;t valid and there is no need to run the hash. Since
the hash function is going to be slower then the luhn check it should
speed things up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rainbow-tables-salts:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Rainbow Tables + Salts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we know that there is a finite number of credit cards, we could
pre-calculate the hash code for every single one of the 10 Quadrillion
possible card values, and store those in a lookup table. Then when ever
I wanted to crack a credit card hash, all i would need is the credit
card hash, and I would be able to figure out the value of that card,
very quickly. Storing all of the known values in a table like this is
called a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rainbow_tables&#34;&gt;Rainbow table&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally if you are going to hash a credit card, don&amp;rsquo;t use SHA-1, or MD5,
use one of the newer SHA versions, SHA-256 or above, and also use a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salt_(cryptography&#34;&gt;salt&lt;/a&gt;). A salt is
basically a second unique value that you always use when hashing, to
generate a different salt then you would normally get with just the
credit card number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I won&amp;rsquo;t have your salt when I generate my rainbow table, my
rainbow table will be no good. It adds yet another layer of security.
Make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t lose your SALT or else you will have to start over
from scratch. Treat your salt like a password, and keep it safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;do-i-really-have-to-worry-about-being-hacked:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Do I really have to worry about being hacked?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a short list of companies that have been hacked recently. If
they can get hacked, so could you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/T.K._Maxx#2007_credit_card_fraud&#34;&gt;TJ
Maxx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bank of America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citigroup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BJ&amp;rsquo;s wholesale club&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hotels.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LexisNexis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polo Ralph Lauren&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wachovoa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heartland_Payment_Systems#Security_breach&#34;&gt;Heartland Payment
Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hannaford&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-could-happen-if-you-were-hacked:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;What could happen if you were Hacked?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Banned from accepting credit cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loss of reputation and customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fines up to \$500,000 per incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Litigation (you could be sued)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-if-i-was-breached:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;What if I was breached?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event of a security incident, merchants must take immediate
action to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contain and limit the exposure. Conduct a thorough investigation of
the suspected or confirmed loss or theft of account information
within 24 hours of the compromise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alert all necessary parties. Be sure to notify: * Merchant Account
Provider * Visa Fraud Control Group at (650) 432-2978 * Local FBI
Office * U.S. Secret Service (if Visa payment data is compromised)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide the compromised Visa accounts to Visa Fraud Control Group
within 24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Within four business days of the reported compromise, provide Visa
with an incident report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;build-pci-complaint-django-applications:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Build PCI Complaint Django Applications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently gave a talk on Build PCI Complaint Django Applications, at
DjangoCon US 2012 in Washington D.C. Here are my slides and the video of
my talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;slides:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;video:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;links:4cd0f426c80b0e9aa5a827b6b948214b&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.akamai.com/html/solutions/security/edge_tokenization.html&#34;&gt;Akamai edge
tokenization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcisecuritystandards.org&#34;&gt;PCI Security Standards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.americanexpress.com/datasecurity&#34;&gt;American Express PCI
pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.discovernetwork.com/fraudsecurity/disc.html&#34;&gt;Discover Financial Services PCI
pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jcb-global.com/english/pci/index.html&#34;&gt;JCB International PCI
pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mastercard.com/sdp&#34;&gt;MasterCard Worldwide PCI pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.visa.com/cisp&#34;&gt;Visa Inc PCI pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.visaeurope.com/ais&#34;&gt;Visa Europe PCI pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>