<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apphosted on KenCochrane.net</title>
    <link>http://www.kencochrane.net/tags/apphosted/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apphosted on KenCochrane.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.kencochrane.net/tags/apphosted/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Django Hosting Roundup: (Ep.io vs Gondor.io vs DotCloud vs Heroku vs AppHosted vs DjangoZoom) Who wins?</title>
      <link>http://www.kencochrane.net/blog/2011/06/django-hosting-roundup-who-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kencochrane.net/blog/2011/06/django-hosting-roundup-who-wins/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;updates:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Updates&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated 2/16/2012: Full disclosure. On Feb 16th 2012, I accepted a
job with dotCloud. I plan on keeping this blog post up to date
and impartial. If you think there are any errors, please let me know
in the comments below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated 1/26/2012: Updated Gondor.io with info from Donald Stufft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated 01/24/2012: changed gondor.io to include SSL support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated 01/01/2012: Added Heroku and updated ep.io, gondor.io,
and dotcloud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past 6 weeks I have been trying out all of the new django/python
hosting services that are currently available today, and I have been
writing about my experiences along the way. It only makes sense to
conclude this series of articles with one last article comparing all of
the services against each other. It is important to note that many of
these services are still in development and aren&amp;rsquo;t even available to the
general public, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep this article up to date as these
services change over time. With that said, don&amp;rsquo;t take my word for it, go
out and try all of these services on your own and find out which one you
like the best, you won&amp;rsquo;t be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;quick-recap:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Quick Recap&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ep-io:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;ep.io&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://kencochrane.net/blog/2011/04/my-experiences-with-epio/&#34;&gt;My Experiences with
ep.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty solid offering, with a nice set of features and a decent price.
Good set of documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Epio closed down on May 31st 2012 ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gondor-io:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;gondor.io&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://kencochrane.net/blog/2011/04/my-day-gondorio/&#34;&gt;My day in
gondor.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their website has a nice list of features that they expect to have once
they officially launch, but most of those features aren&amp;rsquo;t available yet.
The documentation is a little light, but the service has a lot of
potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dotcloud-com:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;dotCloud.com&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://kencochrane.net/blog/2011/04/deploying-my-django-application-to-dotcloud/&#34;&gt;Deploying my Django application to
dotcloud.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have a ton of money ($10M), and with it, a ton of features. They
are very developer friendly, but you need to be pretty technical, it
isn&amp;rsquo;t quite ready for beginners. Good set of documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;strong&gt;Full disclosure&lt;/strong&gt;: I now work for dotCloud]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;apphosted-com:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;AppHosted.com&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://kencochrane.net/blog/2011/05/apphosted-com-django-hosting-review/&#34;&gt;apphosted.com Django Hosting
Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built with security, stability and scalability on their mind from the
beginning. They have a solid offering, and they look to be targeting
enterprise customers who will pay more for that peace of mind. They are
currently lacking some key features, which I&amp;rsquo;m sure they will be adding
soon. Good set of documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;djangozoom-com:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;DjangoZoom.com&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://kencochrane.net/blog/2011/06/djangozoom-com-review/&#34;&gt;DjangoZoom.com
Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built to be fast and easy to use, still missing some key features, but
I&amp;rsquo;m sure they will be available by the time they go live. Decent amount
of documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;heroku-com:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Heroku.com&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://kencochrane.net/blog/2011/11/developers-guide-for-running-django-apps-on-heroku/&#34;&gt;Developers guide for running django apps on
Heroku&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally built as a Ruby on Rails service, they have now added support
for python. The service is still in beta, but it has a lot of potential.
It looks a lot like what dotCloud is offering, with the ability to run
code from almost any language, and a ton of different add-ons for lots
of different services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;awards:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Awards&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fastest-deployments:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Fastest Deployments:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://DjangoZoom.com&#34;&gt;DjangoZoom.com&lt;/a&gt; - Zoom is right, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take
long to configure your application and have it up and running on their
servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;easiest-to-use:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Easiest To Use:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://DjangoZoom.com&#34;&gt;DjangoZoom.com&lt;/a&gt; - No command line interface
needed, just a web browser, a project in a git repo that it has access
too, and a few questions answered and your app is up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-features:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Most Features:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dotcloud.com&#34;&gt;dotCloud.com&lt;/a&gt; - They raised \$10 Million, and they
are spending it on hiring people, buying companies, and building
services. They have a bunch of services currently and they don&amp;rsquo;t plan on
stopping, their roadmap has everything on it, and I think if you give
them enough time they will eventually have a service for everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-developer-friendly:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Most Developer Friendly:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dotcloud.com&#34;&gt;dotCloud.com&lt;/a&gt; - They give lots of features without
handcuffing the developer. They are the only company with full database
and shell access. They do a good job of offering the same type of
service a developer could get if they built it themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;best-overall-value:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Best Overall Value:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ep.io&#34;&gt;ep.io&lt;/a&gt; - This one is hard since most of the services
don&amp;rsquo;t have any pricing listed, but currently ep.io is in the lead, they
offer reasonable prices with a nice Free tier. This allows developers to
try out the service for FREE, as well as run smaller pet projects that
they might not have tried before because they didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pay for
hosting. They have the second most features available, second to only
dotCloud, and there service is pretty solid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;easiest-project-setup:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Easiest Project Setup:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://apphosted.com&#34;&gt;apphosted.com&lt;/a&gt; - Their goal was to make it real
easy to get your project up onto their servers without having to change
your project, and they did that, there was very little if any changes I
needed to make in order to get my application up on their servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;django-feature-hosting-matrix:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Django Feature Hosting Matrix&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make things easier when comparing all of the different services I
have built this matrix with all of the information I compiled from each
of the services. I don&amp;rsquo;t know the answers for all services, but I&amp;rsquo;ll
update it when I find out those answers. If you know the answers feel
free to post a comment to let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have included all of the new django services as well as google app
engine and webfaction.com, a tradition hosting service. This should make
it a little easier to see how these new services compare to other
hosting options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Chart removed since it was out of date]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;who-wins:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Who wins?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is really hard to pick just one winner, mainly because most of these
services are still in beta and not quite finished yet. Also because each
service is a little different, and it will depend on what you are trying
to do. So, go out try them out, and let me know which one you picked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real winner is us, the developers, and the python community in
general. We now have a bunch of really cool services that will make our
lives better, and that is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thank-you:bcec1efcbef3921a30bfadad97f88500&#34;&gt;Thank you!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to thank all of the people who made these services, and gave me
early access to their systems so that I could play around with them. I
wish them the best of luck, and hope they all are really successful, and
they are around for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AppHosted.com Django Hosting Service Review</title>
      <link>http://www.kencochrane.net/blog/2011/05/apphosted-com-django-hosting-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kencochrane.net/blog/2011/05/apphosted-com-django-hosting-review/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post is the fourth in my series about the new Django hosting
services that just recently hit the market. Previously I have reviewed
&lt;a href=&#34;http://kencochrane.net/blog/2011/04/my-experiences-with-epio/&#34;&gt;ep.io&lt;/a&gt; ,
&lt;a href=&#34;http://kencochrane.net/blog/2011/04/my-day-gondorio/&#34;&gt;gondor.io&lt;/a&gt; , and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://kencochrane.net/blog/2011/04/deploying-my-django-application-to-dotcloud/&#34;&gt;dotCloud.com&lt;/a&gt;
.This post reviews &lt;a href=&#34;http://AppHosted.com&#34;&gt;AppHosted.com&lt;/a&gt; , another
similar service that is currently in beta. I was lucky enough to get a
sneak peak of this service before it was released to the general public,
and here are my notes and impressions for the short time I had to play
with the new service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://AppHosted.com&#34;&gt;AppHosted.com&lt;/a&gt; uses a similar concept as the
other django hosting services, they provide you with a command line
client called metro that you use to interact with the service. Like the
other command line clients, it is pretty much just a nice wrapper around
their API, so anything you can do with the metro client you can do with
their API. The client is used to configure your service and push your
files up into their servers. Once the application is created and your
code has been uploaded to their server, you can use their web based
control panel to configure or manage your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that we can compare apples to apples I will go through the process of
installing my blog onto the service so that we can see how it works with
apphosted compared to the other services. It will also hopefully provide
a very simple how to guide on how to install your application onto
AppHosted.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-steps:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;First Steps&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all new projects the first thing that I like to do is create a new
project directory and a new virtual environment for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode bash&#34;&gt;# move into my projects directory
$ cd ~projects/

# make my virtual environment apphosted
$ mkvirtualenv apphosted

# clone my blog
$ hg clone https://bitbucket.org/kencochrane/kencochranenet kencochrane_apphosted

# move into the new project directory
$ cd kencochrane_apphosted
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a local working copy of my blog code and a new virtual
environment I&amp;rsquo;m ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;command-line-interface:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Command Line Interface&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AppHosted has a command line client called Metro, it uses this client to
configure and upload your application onto the apphosted servers. Metro
only has three dependencies: httplib2, paramiko, and pycrypto, if you
don&amp;rsquo;t have them installed pip should handle that for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode bash&#34;&gt;# install the metro client
$ pip install metroclient

Downloading/unpacking metroclient
Running setup.py egg_info for package metroclient
Requirement already satisfied (use --upgrade to upgrade): httplib2 in /Users/ken/.virtualenvs/apphosted/lib/python2.6/site-packages (from metroclient)
Requirement already satisfied (use --upgrade to upgrade): paramiko in /Library/Python/2.6/site-packages (from metroclient)
Requirement already satisfied (use --upgrade to upgrade): pycrypto&amp;gt;=1.9 in /Library/Python/2.6/site-packages (from paramiko-&amp;gt;metroclient)
Installing collected packages: metroclient
Running setup.py install for metroclient
changing mode of build/scripts-2.6/metro from 644 to 755
changing mode of /Users/ken/.virtualenvs/apphosted/bin/metro to 755
Successfully installed metroclient
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;initial-data-django-admin-user:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Initial Data &amp;amp; Django admin user&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment Apphosted.com doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide an easy way to create a
django admin user, in order to create this user in your appHosted.com
database you need to create it on a local database and then export that
data into a fixture called initial_data.json.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode bash&#34;&gt;# locally I run this command to dump the data, so that I can load on app hosted.
$ python manage.py dumpdata &amp;gt; initial_data.json
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another way to create the django admin user, which I&amp;rsquo;ll
describe a little later. This would also be the same way that you would
import any application data that you need in order for your application
to run correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;metro-client:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Metro Client&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the goals for appHosted.com was that they didn&amp;rsquo;t want to require
that you make lots of changes to your project directory structure in
order to use their service. In order to do this they need to do a lot
more work to figure out what it is you want to do, and if they can&amp;rsquo;t
figure it out, they will ask you some questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have our project directory and our initial_data.json file
all ready, lets go ahead and deploy the application. Activate the
virtual environment and go into your project directory. Kick off the
metro client and answer the questions that pop up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode bash&#34;&gt;# run the metro client.
$ metro

Metro Application Manager 1.21
Copyright (c) Lumentica,  http://www.lumentica.com

Application directory (i.e. path to project): ./
Application name: kencochraneblog
Application version: 0.1
Application description: Ken&#39;s AppHosted Blog
Application modules (extra; comma-separated): South==0.7.3, django-activitysync==0.2.2, django-debug-toolbar==0.8.4, django-disqus==0.3.4, django-memcache-status==1.0.1, django-tagging==0.3.1, django-xmlrpc==0.1.2, feedparser==4.1, httplib2==0.6.0, oauth2==1.2.0, python-memcached==1.47, python-twitter==0.8.1, simplejson==2.1.2, wsgiref==0.1.2, yolk==0.4.1, docutils==0.6, Pygments==1.3.1
WSGI module (optional):
Paste config (optional):
Fixtures (optional; comma-separated):
Sync database and load fixtures? (y/n): y
Use SSL? (y/n): n
Force SSL: (y/n): n
Build complete.
Upload to AppHosted? (y/n): y
AppHosted Username: kencochrane
AppHosted Password:
Deploying...
:: Configuring application environment...
:: Configuring application permissions...
:: Configuring application server...
:: Application deployed to server successfully...
:: Application deployment complete...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did this do for us? It takes our application, and uploads it to
their server, and then it installs all of our dependencies that we
listed above. Then it configures it according to our answers, and tries
to start it up, if we told it to, it will sync our database and load our
fixtures. It also takes all of this information and stores it in a file
called metro.config, so that we don&amp;rsquo;t need to type that in every time if
nothing has changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have noticed that I needed to manually enter in all of my
dependencies when prompted, when I asked about this, I was told that if
I didn&amp;rsquo;t enter all of the dependencies it would scan the project for a
pip style requirements.txt file, and use that to load all of your
dependencies. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to test that out yet, since I
already entered my requirements by hand, and once you do it, you don&amp;rsquo;t
need to do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My blog uses south for migration management, and at the time of this
writing there is a bug, and it isn&amp;rsquo;t correctly kicking off the migrate
command during the database sync process. They are aware of the issue
and they are working on a fix, but there is a work around in the
meantime. I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the work around shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your application is deployed it will almost immediately be
available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://&#34;&gt;http://&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;your-app-name&amp;gt;.apphosted.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;log-files:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Log Files&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to view the log files, you need to log into the web control
panel and from there you can download the logs that you are interested
in. At the moment they only support downloading the log files, which is
a little inconvenient, it would be nice to have the ability to tail the
logs, or see the last 50 or 100 lines in the control panel. I asked
about this, and they agreed and said it is on their list of things to
work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;shell-access:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Shell Access&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metro gives you the ability to shell into your application directory, so
that you can kick off django management commands, and other cool things.
One important thing to note is that when you login to the shell, it is a
jailed shell, and you only have access to your own project, and with
limited command access. This is done for security reasons. It is nice to
know that your application runs in it&amp;rsquo;s own jailed area, and no one
else&amp;rsquo;s applications can access your information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up the shell access requires a few steps. Follow these
directions to get the full details:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.apphosted.com/apphosted/apphosted_shell.html&#34;&gt;http://docs.apphosted.com/apphosted/apphosted_shell.html&lt;/a&gt; , but
basically it requires the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create a ssh key if you don&amp;rsquo;t already have one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login to the web console and add your public key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the web console browse over to your application
Settings-&amp;gt;Tools page and click on the “Update Public
Keys” button. (Don&amp;rsquo;t forget about this step, or you won&amp;rsquo;t be able
to login.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the metro client to open the shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: It would be real cool if we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to do step 3, why can&amp;rsquo;t
it automatically update the public keys for all apps? I&amp;rsquo;m guessing it is
a security reason. The first time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t hit the update public keys
button and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why it wasn&amp;rsquo;t working, and luckily one
quick email to the support line, and they let me know what I did wrong,
and I was up and running in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how you can kick off the shell, there are a bunch of command
line args that you can pass as well, just do metro &amp;ndash;help and it will
show them all to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode bash&#34;&gt;$ metro -s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: There is currently a bug that is preventing me from logging into
the shell from my MacBook Pro OS X 10.6.7 using Python 2.6.1 . When I do
it gives me this error. I have informed appHosted, and they said it
looks like an issue with paramiko and python 2.6.1 on the Mac, not sure
if it affects other python versions on other operating systems. They are
working on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode bash&#34;&gt;$ metro -s
Metro Application Manager 1.21
Copyright (c) Lumentica,  http://www.lumentica.com

Application name: kencochraneblog
AppHosted Username: kencochrane
AppHosted Password:
Traceback (most recent call last):
File &amp;quot;/Users/ken/.virtualenvs/apphosted/bin/metro&amp;quot;, line 75, in run_shell
ssh.connect(host, username=app_name, port=port)
File &amp;quot;/Library/Python/2.6/site-packages/paramiko/client.py&amp;quot;, line 278, in connect
for (family, socktype, proto, canonname, sockaddr) in socket.getaddrinfo(hostname, port, socket.AF_UNSPEC, socket.SOCK_STREAM):
gaierror: [Errno 8] nodename nor servname provided, or not known
Error: [Errno 8] nodename nor servname provided, or not known
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;work-arounds:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Work Arounds&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know how to shell into your application, you can also kick
off django management commands. I mentioned earlier that there was
another way to create the django admin user, well here is how you do it.
Login to the metro shell and then kick off the createsuperuser django
management command. Logging into the shell and finding things isn&amp;rsquo;t easy
do to the added security so to save you some trouble this is what I did.
Python isn&amp;rsquo;t in your path so you need to put the fully qualified path to
the virtual env&amp;rsquo;s python. Not sure if the jailed shell allows you to
edit your .profile if so, it might be nice to configure this so that you
don&amp;rsquo;t always have to do the full path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode bash&#34;&gt;# Create superuser (django admin)
$ /ve/kencochraneblog/bin/python /app/kencochraneblog/mysite/manage.py createsuperuser

# kicking off south migrations by hand.
$ /ve/kencochraneblog/bin/python /app/kencochraneblog/mysite/manage.py migrate
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My application&amp;rsquo;s name is kencochraneblog, so make sure you replace my
application name with yours, it should be something like this. replace
app_name,django_project_dir and command with your variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sourceCode bash&#34;&gt;$ /ve/&amp;lt;app_name&amp;gt;/bin/python /app/&amp;lt;app_name&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;django_project_dir&amp;gt;/manage.py &amp;lt;command&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;background-tasks:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Background Tasks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AppHosted also supports background tasks via celery, they don&amp;rsquo;t have the
documentation created yet, but it should be available soon. They are
also planning on supporting a cron like service, not sure if it will be
cron, or something similar, but it should do, what you need it to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;api:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;API&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AppHosted provides a pretty nice API that allows you to do anything that
the metro client does. This will allow you to write your own automation
and management scripts to interact with your application. If you
practice continuous deployment, it will allow you to automatically
deploy the latest version of code on a post commit hook, if all of your
tests pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;services:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Services&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now they only support memcache for caching, and PostgreSQL for
databases, but they plan on adding more services as they move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been playing with AppHosted for a few weeks now, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty
happy with what they have so far. They still have a few issues to work
out and they are still a work in progress, but I have been seeing
improvements all of the time, so it will only be a matter of time before
they are ready for the general public. Every time I came across an
issue, they were quick to reply to my emails and solve my issues, or
tell me where I was going wrong. If you have any more questions I
recommend checking out their documentation @
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.apphosted.com/index.html&#34;&gt;http://docs.apphosted.com/index.html&lt;/a&gt; . Check them out, and make sure
you let me know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are now open to the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;update:fd2d20709a7d24937bf602503a235c47&#34;&gt;Update:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read how this service stacks up against other services like it in my
&lt;a href=&#34;http://kencochrane.net/blog/2011/06/django-hosting-roundup-who-wins/&#34;&gt;Django hosting
roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2/16/2012: Full disclosure. On Feb 16th 2012, I accepted a job with
dotCloud a competitor to apphosted. I plan on keeping this blog post up
to date and impartial. If you think there are any errors, please let me
know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>